<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ubuntu Budgie &#8211; Ubuntu Budgie</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/ubuntu-budgie/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 16:19:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ubwc.svg</url>
	<title>Ubuntu Budgie &#8211; Ubuntu Budgie</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Ubuntu Budgie 23.10 Released!</title>
		<link>/2023/10/ubuntu-budgie-23-10-released/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 14:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[23.10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are pleased to announce the release of the next version of our distro, the 23.10 release. This is a standard release supported for 9 months packed full of all sorts of new capabilities. If you want a well tested and longer term support then our 22.04 LTS version is supported for 3 years. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce the release of the next version of our distro, the 23.10 release. This is a standard release supported for 9 months packed full of all sorts of new capabilities. If you want a well tested and longer term support then our 22.04 LTS version is supported for 3 years. The new release has many new core updates as well as v10.8 version of budgie itself: We&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="/2023/10/ubuntu-budgie-23-10-released/" rel="nofollow">Source</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ubuntu Budgie 23.04 Released!</title>
		<link>/2023/04/ubuntu-budgie-23-04-released/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 21:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[23.04]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3296</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are pleased to announce the release of the next version of our distro, the 23.04 release for both the desktop and Raspberry Pi4. This is a standard release supported for 9 months packed full of all sorts of new capabilities. If you want a well tested and longer term support then our 22.04.2 LTS [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce the release of the next version of our distro, the 23.04 release for both the desktop and Raspberry Pi4. This is a standard release supported for 9 months packed full of all sorts of new capabilities. If you want a well tested and longer term support then our 22.04.2 LTS version is supported for 3 years. New with this release is a full backport of all the&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="/2023/04/ubuntu-budgie-23-04-released/" rel="nofollow">Source</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ubuntu Budgie 22.10 Released!</title>
		<link>/2022/10/ubuntu-budgie-22-10-released/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 17:19:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[22.10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are pleased to announce the release of the next version of our distro, the 22.10 release. This is a standard release supported for 9 months packed full of all sorts of new capabilities. If you want a well tested and longer term support then our 22.04.1 LTS version is supported for 3 years. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce the release of the next version of our distro, the 22.10 release. This is a standard release supported for 9 months packed full of all sorts of new capabilities. If you want a well tested and longer term support then our 22.04.1 LTS version is supported for 3 years. The new release has many new core updates as well as a bleeding edge version of budgie itself&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="/2022/10/ubuntu-budgie-22-10-released/" rel="nofollow">Source</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ubuntu Budgie 22.10 Release Notes</title>
		<link>/2022/09/ubuntu-budgie-22-10-release-notes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 19:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[22.04]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jammy Jellyfish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie 22.04]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction and overview Ubuntu Budgie 22.10 (Kinetic Kudu) is a normal release with 9 months of support, from October 2022 to July 2023. Ubuntu LTS releases are focused on long term support. If stability is more important than having the latest and greatest version of the kernel, desktop environment, and applications then Ubuntu Budgie 22.04 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ubuntu Budgie 22.10 (Kinetic Kudu) is a normal release with 9 months of support, from October 2022 to July 2023. Ubuntu LTS releases are focused on long term support. If stability is more important than having the latest and greatest version of the kernel, desktop environment, and applications then Ubuntu Budgie 22.04 LTS is perfect for you. In these release notes, we are going to cover the&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="/2022/09/ubuntu-budgie-22-10-release-notes/" rel="nofollow">Source</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>CoreCtrl repository changes</title>
		<link>/2022/09/corectrl-repository-changes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mauro]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 13:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Budgie Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Budgie Welcome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Linux Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2827</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Premise We recently introduced our Ubuntu Budgie Welcome Gaming app. It is an easy way for Ubuntu Budgie users to install useful games, gaming clients and tools. One of the tools included is CoreCtrl. CoreCtrl is a software that allows us to control hardware via application profiles. You can learn more about CoreCtrl on its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We recently introduced our Ubuntu Budgie Welcome Gaming app. It is an easy way for Ubuntu Budgie users to install useful games, gaming clients and tools. One of the tools included is CoreCtrl. CoreCtrl is a software that allows us to control hardware via application profiles. You can learn more about CoreCtrl on its gitlab page. CoreCtrl is available for Ubuntu via mesarc PPA.</p>
<p><a href="/2022/09/corectrl-repository-changes/" rel="nofollow">Source</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ubuntu 22.04 Release Notes for 20.04 upgraders</title>
		<link>/2022/04/ubuntu-22-04-release-notes-for-20-04-upgraders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mauro]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 21:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie 20.04]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie 22.04]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie Upgrade]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction and overview Ubuntu Budgie 22.04 LTS (Jammy Jellyfish) is a Long Term Support release with 3 years of support, from April 2022 to April 2025. This is the 20.04 upgraders release note. This takes the 20.10/21.04 and 21.10 release notes and highlights the key parts that 20.04 upgraders need to be aware of. If [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ubuntu Budgie 22.04 LTS (Jammy Jellyfish) is a Long Term Support release with 3 years of support, from April 2022 to April 2025. This is the 20.04 upgraders release note. This takes the 20.10/21.04 and 21.10 release notes and highlights the key parts that 20.04 upgraders need to be aware of. If you are upgrading from 21.10 we have a release note more applicable to you! In these release notes&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="/2022/04/ubuntu-22-04-release-notes-for-20-04-upgraders/" rel="nofollow">Source</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ubuntu Budgie 22.04 LTS Release Notes</title>
		<link>/2022/03/ubuntu-budgie-22-04-lts-release-notes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mauro]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 12:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[22.04]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jammy Jellyfish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie 22.04]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction and overview Ubuntu Budgie 22.04 LTS (Jammy Jellyfish) is a Long Term Support release with 3 years of support, from April 2022 to April 2025. Ubuntu LTS releases are focused on long term support, therefore stability is more important than having latest and greatest version of kernel, desktop environment, and applications. In these release [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ubuntu Budgie 22.04 LTS (Jammy Jellyfish) is a Long Term Support release with 3 years of support, from April 2022 to April 2025. Ubuntu LTS releases are focused on long term support, therefore stability is more important than having latest and greatest version of kernel, desktop environment, and applications. In these release notes, we are going to cover the following items: If you are&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="/2022/03/ubuntu-budgie-22-04-lts-release-notes/" rel="nofollow">Source</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A deep dive in our new Budgie Gaming Application</title>
		<link>/2022/03/a-deep-dive-in-our-new-budgie-gaming-application/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mauro]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Budgie Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Budgie Welcome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Linux Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a follow up post of our previous article Quick overview of Budgie Welcome Application. As you might know, our team has been working to improve gaming experience. I am here today to take you through our journey. Soon after I joined the team, mid 2021, I was discussing with David and Nikola about [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a follow up post of our previous article Quick overview of Budgie Welcome Application. As you might know, our team has been working to improve gaming experience. I am here today to take you through our journey. Soon after I joined the team, mid 2021, I was discussing with David and Nikola about an idea to add gaming recommendations to our Ubuntu Budgie Welcome application.</p>
<p><a href="/2022/03/a-deep-dive-in-our-new-budgie-gaming-application/" rel="nofollow">Source</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Automate System Updates on Ubuntu Desktop</title>
		<link>/2022/03/automate-system-updates-on-ubuntu-desktop/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mauro]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 16:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tutorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unattended Upgrades]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2669</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction Please note this configuration below is suitable for desktops. For servers, we would need to dig a bit deeper in options, systemd services, timers, email notifications, automatic reboot, and more. Also, I strongly recommended to take system snapshots with Timeshift on a daily basis, and Clonezilla every month. Goals Our goal is the following: [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Please note this configuration below is suitable for desktops. For servers, we would need to dig a bit deeper in options, systemd services, timers, email notifications, automatic reboot, and more. Also, I strongly recommended to take system snapshots with Timeshift on a daily basis, and Clonezilla every month. Our goal is the following: Automate cleanup of old kernels, system updates&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="/2022/03/automate-system-updates-on-ubuntu-desktop/" rel="nofollow">Source</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ubuntu Budgie and  Orchis theme deliver a smooth, elegant desktop experience</title>
		<link>/2021/12/ubuntu-budgie-and-orchis-theme-deliver-a-smooth-elegant-desktop-experience/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mauro]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 14:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Other]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Budgie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orchis Theme]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu Budgie]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With this quick write up I am going to show you a theme we recently added to Ubuntu Budgie. Vinceliuice, the author of this theme, delivered an awesome GTK/GNOME theme called Orchis. And how could we miss it? As soon as we saw it, we asked David to get it in our &#34;Themes and Layouts&#34; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With this quick write up I am going to show you a theme we recently added to Ubuntu Budgie. Vinceliuice, the author of this theme, delivered an awesome GTK/GNOME theme called Orchis. And how could we miss it? As soon as we saw it, we asked David to get it in our &quot;Themes and Layouts&quot; Application. Before we knew it, David included it, and by now all users of 20.04, 21.04 and 21.10&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="/2021/12/ubuntu-budgie-and-orchis-theme-deliver-a-smooth-elegant-desktop-experience/" rel="nofollow">Source</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
